What is that?
Tournaments have been held
in each of the last 15 years,
and, in all that time,
East Gorteau has yet to lose.
They are now
on their third representative,
who is a five-time reigning champion.
Hmm. So then if I defeat this champion,
I'll be the best in the world?
A fitting end to this diversion.
Call them.
[opening theme music playing]
[singer singing in Japanese]
[singer singing in English]
CHECK X AND X MATE
the King has spent this time
in his palace,
defeating masters of shogi,
go, and other board games.
has just been summoned.
[sniffs]
You and I will play Gungi,
but I'm learning the rules now,
so you must wait.
[Komugi] Oh! I'm so sorry.
and I'm always saying the wrong thing.
[grunts]
[wind blowing]
[King] Okay, I got the gist of it.
What's the matter now?
[Komugi] Gosh.
That was pretty embarrassing.
Like I said, I'm not that smart.
My folks are always yelling at me.
[sniffles]
[King] Just start.
Right!
It's a real honor to play against you.
No, not at all.
So would you please
announce your moves for me?
I can't help but keep them open,
not while I'm playing,
but if that's unacceptable,
I can try…
[Komugi] Soldier four-four-one.
[wind blowing]
[Knuckle] So you can't reach him at all?
[Gon] No. His phone must be off.
I guess we did agree that
he'd always initiate contact,
so it's not all that surprising.
[Meleoron] The hell?
Why does that guy look like he was born
in the wrong decade?
By the look on his face,
he's the kind of guy
who's always looking for a fight.
makes it look like he's scared
and suspicious of everything.
I doubt he'll ever give me
a chance to explain myself.
Whatever I say will
probably just go in one ear
and come out the other.
I hate to say it, Gon,
but my first impressions
are super bad.
[dog whimpers]
[Meleoron] Eh?
[whimpering]
Hey, what's going on?
[Knuckle] Beats me.
It's just a pack of strays, I guess.
But they're all wearing collars.
[Shoot] What he's not telling you
is that he's been feeding
all the animals left behind
due to the sorting,
even though it cuts into his sleep.
Eh, shut up! Not all of 'em.
We don't have time to waste on that crap.
Don't you think I know that?
So I gave up on the ones
that had no chance.
Aren't you proud of me?
Some were just skin and bones
and refused to eat what I offered 'em.
And then there were the stupid, loyal ones
who refused to leave their homes
even after I unchained 'em.
What's so bad about saving
the ones that want the help?
[voice breaking] Tell me that!
You wanna get smacked in the head? [sobs]
[Meleoron] Hmph.
That's not enough
to change my opinion of him.
Well, maybe a little.
And now shinobi, seven-eight-two.
That's checkmate.
GENERAL
SHINOBI
[King] A strategy to stack a bow
as a basis for attack and defense,
a typical Yagura castle.
Nothing particularly striking
in that strategy.
The opening array
was by the book as well…
We will play another.
Yes! I would be happy to.
[Gungi piece clatter]
[Komugi] Cavalry, eight-eight-one.
That's checkmate.
I'm surprised. You're such a fast learner.
Congratulations, supreme leader.
[King]
That's enough. Go get some rest.
Huh?
[sniffles] There's no need.
I'm fine to keep playing if you want to.
I've played gungi for three days
without sleep before.
I have a rematch.
Once I've finished with him,
you'll have your turn.
Oh.
Then I will rest.
I'm sure it will do me good.
There are several strategies,
but it's basically the same
as all the other games.
A few more rounds, and I'll be able
to make her play for real.
Once I do,
I'll be able to observe her rhythm.
ARCHER
[dramatic music playing]
[narrator] In the palace,
the King continues to play
against the Gungi master,
hoping to hone his skills.
[Morel] Deep purple.
[inhales]
[grunts]
so in the event that the enemy retaliates,
I can maintain 50 of them at once,
and they're highly effective.
One big advantage to doing it this way
is that En can't differentiate
between one of these and a human being.
But chimera ants are still ants,
so Neferpitou won't leave the King's side.
So restricting the movement
of the royal guard
should be a piece of cake.
The only question is,
how will the King respond?
If he's impulsive,
it'll be harder to anticipate his actions.
But as long as they keep
these coming, we're fine.
[intense music playing]
Hey, it's been a while.
It's really good to see you.
[scoffs] He's leveled up.
The air around him
feels totally different.
Knuckle's A.P.R. is gone.
if something bad had happened.
If A.P.R. is gone,
I'll beat you down first…
and then the pompadour will be next.
[Morel] There must be a reason
he's so confident.
We'll see about that.
If that ability is to exorcise Nen,
we're in big trouble.
I was really hoping that our strategy
would be effective against the King.
However, if he can exorcise Nen,
this is a golden opportunity.
If I neutralize him now,
Knuckle and Shoot's strategy
could still work.
I have to do it.
I can't deactivate deep purple,
so I'll have to get by
on my remaining aura.
[grunts]
Now you're the one who's it for a change.
I'm what? What are you saying?
[dramatic music playing]
[rumbling]
Huh?
Where the hell am I?
Looks like a savannah.
Did he teleport me?
If this is his new ability,
a different chimera ant
is the Nen exorcist.
You have eight hours.
Hey, didn't you hear
what I just said to you?
You can't leave here
without touching me first!
Those are the rules!
I guess I could chase you,
but I'd still never be able to catch you,
so might as well take my time.
[groans]
[Leol] Cheetu activated his ability.
I don't know what it does,
but they won't be back
for another eight hours.
[dramatic music playing]
[Morel] The backdrop's a wall.
It looks like I'm in some kind of space
separated from the real world,
just like he said.
Seems to be about the size
of a baseball field.
for me to deactivate Deep Purple
from within this space?
It's too risky to try.
Huh?
[Morel] I can't deactivate Deep Purple,
at least, not yet.
Well, well.
Are you finally ready to start?
You're just wasting time.
You can't destroy the hourglass or wall.
It's like I said.
There's only one way out,
and if you don't catch me,
you're gonna be stuck here.
[Morel] His ability was clearly influenced
by Knuckle's Hakoware,
Chapter Seven Bankruptcy, so…
Looks like there's more to this ability.
This might take a while.
[groans] Are you messing with me?
[snoring]
[growls]
[Morel chuckles]
Go ahead. Lose your temper.
It's starting to look
like you don't understand
your own ability.
This is not a battle of speed.
This is a contest of wills.
[running footsteps]
[Knov] Deep purple is still activated…
so the plan continues.
[tense music playing]
A man in a suit
with black hair and glasses.
[Leol] Anyone else?
[Flutter] No. Just him,
along with the figures in white.
[Leol] Those white figures
are probably nothing
but ordinary soldiers.
But it is possible
that the true leader is concealed
among them.
No matter what,
I can't let anyone see my ability,
and Hirin can't go out after
exorcising the Nen from Cheetu.
and after that, he might even decide
to come out there and play himself.
We'll be there to protect him,
of course,
but you never really know
what might happen.
Our preference is for the King
to remain inside
[Neferpitou] Go give Leol a hand.
[Welfin] Right.
[Bloster] As you wish.
Hmm.
[Shaiapouf] This player is a true master.
[Komugi] Two-eight-two, fort.
Impossible.
There were only 144 moves,
start to finish.
This could only have happened
if she predicted my game from the start.
[Neferpitou] A storm is brewing.
[narrator] The girl's strength
upsets the King,
[singer singing in Japanese]
[Gon] Next time, "Doubt and Hesitation."
[Gon and Killua] Please, go easy on me.
-[Gon] Clack!
-[Killua] Whack!
-[Gon] Klickety-clack clack!
-[Killua] Bam!
[singer singing in Japanese]